Lilith 0.9.37

Download Now!
(Released: 2009-11-xx)

Changes

Change of active Conditions was not repainting views. This was only the case in internal betas.
This was reported by Alfred.
(Ticket 75)
Removed additivity from the debug loggers. Debug logger events won't show up in the Lilith log or the console.
Prevented duplicate start of application by the same user.
Duplicate startup by a different user is still possible but quite useless until the event receivers are configurable.
This was requested by Joe.
(Ticket 74)
Enhanced debug dialog. Better layout and tooltips.
Added option to disable the creation of statistics.
(Ticket 4)
Added "Copy call location" action. This is quite useful in combination with the CallLocation condition.
Added CallLocation condition that returns true if the first element of the call stack equals the given StackTraceElement.
Added option to disable global logs.
This was requested by Joe.
(Ticket 73)
Preventing saved conditions with duplicate name or condition.
The Appenders are now supporting the "Adder-Idiom" that is common for Logback appenders.
You can now use multiple <RemoteHost> tags to define the remote hosts.
Replaced JCheckboxMenuItem in Window menu with a JMenuItem containing an Icon if the entry has a frame.
Toolbar of mainframe was not switched active after attach.
(Ticket 71)
Toolbar of mainframe stayed active after detach.
(Ticket 70)
Removed appBuildNumber from title. It was annoying at best.
Enhanced "Check for update" dialog.
(Ticket 68)
Implement optional "Tip of the Day" dialog.
(Ticket 22)
Added "Level>=" as a native default condition to increase performance.
Copy actions are now working correctly in case of external frames.
This was reported by Matthias "Alfred" Neumann.
(Ticket 67)
Updated protobuf to 2.2.0.
Jumping to the unfiltered event didn't work the first time if Tail was enabled.
This was reported by Joe.
(Ticket 66)
Preferences dialog can now be closed by pressing Enter.
This was suggested by Vlad Satanovski.
Table and message view are now having reasonable preferred sizes (needed because of splitpane).
Replaced tabs of event view with a combobox.
The combobox is only visible if there are filtered views. There's also more room for the condition string.
Something like this was suggested by Scott Stanton and Joe.
(Ticket 58)
Added "Execute GC" to Troubleshooting.
Added option to show/hide the statusbar.
Added option to show/hide the toolbar.
This was suggested by Scott Stanton, Ekkehard Gentz and Joe.
(Ticket 57)
Added "Context" column for logging events.
Updated keyboard help. Better symbol for "Ctrl"/"cmd".
Added "Troubleshooting..." menu item in "Help" menu as a shortcut to the throubleshooting section of Preferences.
(Ticket 65)
Added new command "Copy Properties" to Troubleshooting section of Preferences.
(Ticket 65)
Removed useless Statistics action for current source. Statistics can be obtained using "Window" > "Statistics".
(Ticket 24)
Added persistent zoom-in (*command* .) and zoom-out (*command* shift .) of details view.
(Ticket 59)
Events did sometimes show up twice in filtered views. This was caused by a classic off-by-one error.
Reported by Joe.
(Ticket 64)
Fixed a remaining hang in the multiplex appenders in case of certain network problems.
Updated Groovy to 1.6.5.
Updated Logback to 0.9.17.
This fixes issue 63 that was caused by a Logback bug. Thanks for the fast fix, Ceki!
(Ticket 63)

Known Issues

Mac OS X 10.5 + 10.6:
Shortcuts/Accelerators are not working if both the "Tip of the Day" and "Check for Update" dialogs show after startup.
This seems to be a bug in the Java implementation from Apple.
See Ticket 72.
Selection in the HTML view is currently somewhat buggy, especially in case of scaled view. This is a limitation of Flying Saucer that's used as the XHTML renderer.

Previous Versions

0.9.36

Lilith 0.9.38

Download Now!
(Released: 2010-03-26)

Changes

Added help about using Lilith encoders in FileAppender.
Added detection of outdated index files and the option to reindex a log file in that case.
This is helpful while reopening log files created by a FileAppender.
Added new modules de.huxhorn.lilith.logback.encoder.classic and de.huxhorn.lilith.logback.encoder.access to support writing of Lilith logfiles using Logback FileAppender.
Thanks to Ceki for supporting this!
(Ticket 23)
Added some more tips.
Added shortcut for "Close all" action.
Views aren't opened anymore in case of connection closed for black- or not whitelisted sources.
This was reported by Vlad Satanovski.
(Ticket 76)
Added the ability to clear a filtered view. Doing this clears the original view and resets the filtered view.
This was suggested by Joe.
Moved BufferTableModel to new module sulky-buffers-table.
Moved RowBasedTableModel and PersistentTableColumnModel to module sulky-swing.
Implemented the workaround for Apple Problem ID #7240026 suggested by GalaJon.
Thanks a lot!
See his answer on stackoverflow.com.
(Ticket 72)
Of-by-one error in message renderer [+x lines].
Lilith log is now showing uncaught exceptions as errors.
Added "Uncaught Exception" debug action.
The find panel has been heavily refactored.
Instead of a text-field it now features a combobox containing the previous 15 searches that were used for filtered views. Additionally, there's a new filter type "Named" that populates the combobox with named/saved conditions. Similarly, selecting "Level>=" populates the combobox with the correct values from TRACE to ERROR. The comboboxes, both filter type selection and filter text, feature autocompletion of entered text.
This was suggested by Joe.
(Ticket 50)
Groovy 1.7.0
Logback 0.9.19
SLF4J 1.5.11

Known Issues

Selection in the HTML view is currently somewhat buggy, especially in case of scaled view. This is a limitation of Flying Saucer that's used as the XHTML renderer.

Previous Versions

0.9.37
0.9.36

Lilith 0.9.39

Download Now!
(Released: 2010-05-12)

Changes

Added some error messages.
Added "recent files" menu.
This was requested by Jeff Jensen (jeffjensen).
(Ticket 83)
lilith.bat does not strictly require a %JAVA_HOME% environment variable anymore.
This was requested by Gareth Doutch (gdoutch).
(Ticket 80)
Added special icons for views opened from a file, different ones for refreshing (Lilith) and non-refreshing (imported) ones.
They arguably suck a little bit. ;)
(Ticket 48)
Added automatic refreshing of opened Lilith files. This should work but isn't tested very thoroughly, yet.
This was requested by Jeff Jensen (jeffjensen).
(Ticket 84)
Added cat (-c) and tail (-t, -f) functionality to Lilith so it's possible to print entries of binary Lilith log-files to the console. Number of printed entries can be configured using -n. The format string of for the event can be given at runtime.
Unfortunately, this is only possible with Logback-Classic, not Logback-Access.
The reason for this shortcoming is LBACCESS-12.

The following parts of LoggingEvent aren't supported yet:

LoggerContextVO
IThrowableProxy
Marker

Removed LogbackClassic appender from default logback.xml of Lilith to prevent warning during startup. Those would be especially annoying in case of cat or tail.
This is a workaround for LBCLASSIC-156.
Changed autocomplete of find combos from uber-annoying case-insensitive swingx to much less annoying case-sensitive Glazed Lists.
This annoyed Alfred and me.
Neither "Window" menu nor status bar did update properly if "Automatically open new views on connection." was deselected.
This bug was found by Joe.
(Ticket 82)
Changed the license of all files previously licensed as LGPLv3 to both LGPLv3 and ASLv2 instead. Use whichever license suits you better.
This was requested by Ekkehard Gentz.
Added option to maximize internal frames by default. This is actually very good idea!
This was suggested by snstanton.
(Ticket 77)
Added contextName and/or applicationIdentifier to the title of the frames.
This was suggested by Alfred & Joe.
It wasn't possible to cancel an exit-request executed by closing the main frame.
This bug was found by Gareth Doutch (gdoutch).
(Ticket 79)
Replaced all <layout> with <encoder> in logback*.xml.
See Logback documentation for info.
Logback 0.9.21
SLF4J 1.6.0
commons-cli 1.2
httpclient 4.0.1
Groovy 1.7.2

Known Issues

Selection in the HTML view is currently somewhat buggy, especially in case of scaled view. This is a limitation of Flying Saucer that's used as the XHTML renderer.
cat and tail are currently still experimental features.
AccessEvent isn't (and can't be) supported yet. LoggingEvent isn't fully supported, either.

Previous Versions

0.9.38
0.9.37
0.9.36

Next Version

0.9.40

Lilith 0.9.40

Download Now!
(Released: 2010-xx-xx)

Changes

Color-Schemes (as used by saved conditions, for example) can now be defined partially, i.e. one condition can set a border while the text-color might be defined by a different condition.
Maps, e.g. MDC, are now sorted by key-value in the details view.
This was suggested by Joe.
Added preferences to check for pre-release versions in addition to release versions. Off by default.
Added -T/--print-timestamp command line argument that prints the timestamp and date of build.
If the used version is a SNAPSHOT, Lilith will always check for a new SNAPSHOT pre-release regardless of the "Check for updates on startup." settings.
Enhanced "Check for update" functionality.
No more false update warnings in case of SNAPSHOT pre-releases. A new release takes precedence over a new pre-release.
SNAPSHOT pre-releases will now contain the date and time of the build in the window title.
Added support for java.util.logging SocketHandler. Lilith is listening on port 11020 for incoming connections.
I'd still recommend to switch to SLF4J/Logback, though!
(Ticket 35)
Added JSON-Appenders and JSON-Receivers.
Lilith is listening for message-based JSON-Events on port 10030 (uncompressed) and 10031 (compressed).
Zero-delimited JSON-Events are consumed on port 11010.
Check out the expected JSON data.
Replaced Commons-CLI with JCommander. Very nice replacement.
I'd like to take this opportunity to thank Cédric Beust for his great (and fast!) support!
You should seriously check JCommander out if your application is handling command line arguments at all.
Added support for Log4j SocketAppender. Lilith is listening on port 4445 for incoming connections.
I'd still recommend to switch to SLF4J/Logback, though!
(Ticket 32)
Fixed glitch in case of "Find next"/"Find prev" while search is already running. Additional searches are now ignored.
Added "Find previous active" (*command* T) and "Find next active" (*command* shift T) functionality to quickly jump to events that match any active condition.
(Ticket 93)
Added "Export" functionality which exports the currently selected view into a Lilith file.
(Ticket 92)
Added default condition name to preferences. It's preselected for every new view.
This was suggested by Lothar Cezanne.
Polling events every 100ms instead of every 2s.
This results in less congestion and a much snappier feeling.
Fixed deployment of site.
See sulky and lilith.
Added --export-preferences <file> and --import-preferences <file> commandline options to be able to export and import all preferences.
This was requested by Gareth Doutch (gdoutch).
(Ticket 81)
Added an additional executable lilith-all.jar containing all dependencies as another download option.
This was requested by Adrien Sales.
Added ability to define a sound for WARN-level events, but without any assigned default sound.
This was requested by Adrien Sales.
Added F1 as shortcut for Help.
This was requested by Adrien Sales.
Fixed several issues in case of log files that are recreated by <append>false</append> in FileAppender.
Those were all raised by Jeff Jensen (jeffjensen). Thank you very much!
(Ticket 84, Ticket 88, Ticket 90)
Fixed the regression that the internal Lilith log wouldn't show up in the menu anymore.
(Ticket 85)
Changed update interval of opened files from 5 seconds to 1 second.
Spring 3.0.5.RELEASE
Groovy 1.7.5
SLF4J 1.6.1
Logback 0.9.26

Known Issues

Selection in the HTML view is currently somewhat buggy, especially in case of scaled view. This is a limitation of Flying Saucer that's used as the XHTML renderer.
cat and tail are currently still experimental features.
AccessEvent isn't (and can't be) supported yet. LoggingEvent isn't fully supported, either.

Previous Versions

0.9.39
0.9.38
0.9.37
0.9.36

Lilith 0.9.41

Download Now!
(Released: 2011-05-02)

This is an interim release because of a rather critical bug discovered by Andy Goossens.
Webapps using a ClassicMultiplexSocketAppender would not undeploy properly because of a dangling classloader.
I originally wanted to wait for Logback 0.9.29 due to the issues with 0.9.28 described in "Known Issues" below but I was unable to get any ETA for the next release.

Changes

The NDC behavior has changed a bit since it does not inherit the NDC of the parent threads anymore. This is actually a better behavior. Inheriting does not make much sense for an NDC - in contrast to MDC where it is very helpful - since it resembles a contextual "stacktrace".
I never documented the previous behavior, anyway. Problem? ;)
Fixed two classloader-leak-issues that prevented proper unloading of webapps upon undeploy/redeploy.

The threads startet by the Lilith multiplex appenders did stop but I didn't bother to wait until they finished doing so. This has been fixed now. All threads are destroyed before stop() returns.
I had an issue in the NDC implementation that was very comparable to the one that caused LBCLASSIC-183.
I was putting an instance of a class loaded by the webapp classloader into a ThreadLocal. I fixed this by using two ThreadLocals, a ThreadLocal<String> and a ThreadLocal<String[]>, instead of my own class.

This issue was discovered and reported by Andy Goossens. Thank you very much!
(Ticket #96)
Minimize to system tray.
Added support for (optional, default is on) system tray icon. Double-clicking the icon hides/shows all windows. The menu also contains a Quit action. If system tray icon is active (supported and enabled) then closing the main frame does not exit the application. This will now hide all windows, instead.
This was requested by Adrien Sales and Joe.
(Ticket #91)
Implemented custom "Copy to clipboard" functionality using Groovy.
This was suggested by Joe.
Added support for cat/tail of Lilith AccessEvent files.
Better generation of message tooltip. Content is not tailed anymore.
Colors of logging level and access status type are now configurable.
(Ticket #5)
Importing gzipped java.util.logging or log4j xml is now supported.
Using JComboBox & CardLayout instead of JTabbedPane in Preferences Dialog.
"Go to Source" is now executed asynchronously.
Joe nagged me about this. ;)
(Ticket #12)
Detached windows were using the popup menu of the main frame.
They are now using the popup menu of the detached frame as originally intended.
This bug was found by Dimi.
(Ticket #95)
Added messagePattern.contains condition and "Copy message pattern" action. Using message pattern for filtering is faster than using message.
Using Mensch font by @robey (Robey Pointer) as the monospace font of the HTML View.
HTML View is now anti-aliasing the fonts.
Logback 0.9.28
Groovy 1.8.0
AspectJ 1.6.10, Jackson 1.7.1, JCommander 1.17, JGoodies Looks 2.2.2, commons-lang 2.6, commons-io 2.0.1, httpclient 4.1, httpcore 4.1

Known Issues

The Logback error message on startup is caused by LBCLASSIC-246 introduced in 0.9.28 and will be fixed in Logback 0.9.29.
cat and tail are currently still experimental features.

LoggingEvent isn't fully supported, yet.
See LBCLASSIC-257

Flying Saucer related issues:

Selection in the HTML view is currently somewhat buggy, especially in case of scaled view.
See Issue 79: SelectionHighlighter not compatible with ScalableXHTMLPanel
The first line of the message in HTML view is not properly indented if it starts with whitespace. You can see this effect by examining the event created by LogPinupLargeRunnable (executed via "Log ASCII"). The HTML created is actually correct.
See Issue 125: <pre> ignores leading whitespace
Jumping to anchors is currently not supported so the navigation in help and details view isn't as good as it could be.
See Issue 105: URLs with anchors

Lilith may hang during startup while creating the preferences dialog. Just restart Lilith in that rare case.
This is caused by bug #6995182 and I can't do anything about it.
Sorry about it. It's a stupid Java-MediaTracker-ColorChooser-Bug with no workaround available.
m(

Previous Versions

0.9.40
0.9.39
0.9.38
0.9.37
0.9.36

Lilith 0.9.42

Download Now!
(Released: 2012-03-12)

Changes

tail and cat are now fully supporting both LoggingEvent and AccessEvent.
Restored Logback SocketAppender in Lilith logging configuration. It's now triggered during debug actions, again.
Added support for new Java SE 7 try-with-resources statement suppressed Throwables.
See Better Resource Management with Java SE 7: Beyond Syntactic Sugar.
This is not sufficient, yet, since Logback (and my corresponding converter) needs to add support, too.
See https://github.com/ceki/logback/pull/16 and LBCLASSIC-276.
After many runs that replace opened log file, Updating task failed with "Negative seek offset"
This was reported by Jeff Jensen (jeffjensen).
(Ticket #97)
Added "Focus..." and "Exclude..." menus to popup.
(Ticket #52)
"Edit", "Copy..." and "Filter..." menus are only enabled if it makes sense.
Added "Copy event as JSON" and "Copy event as XML".
This was requested by Joe.
Added lilith.timestamp.milliseconds system property.
Preventing multiple warning log-entries in case of broken groovy files (detailsView.groovy, Conditions, ClipboardFormatter).
Instead, a warning is only emitted once for every file change.
Instances aren't recreated in that case, either, so this also enhances the performance and lowers the CPU usage during general use.
Views are now properly updated upon preferences change.
Added option for "wrapped exception style" in details view.
This was suggested by Tomasz Nurkiewicz in LBCLASSIC-217.
(Ticket #100)
Changed NDC to use varargs.
Added nottingham-draft HTTP status codes.
See https://tools.ietf.org/html/draft-nottingham-http-new-status-04
Relaxed namespace handling of all XML readers. This enables retrieval of old (1.3) Lilith XML Events.
This fixes a problem reported by Ekkehard Gentz.
All KeyStrokes are now managed globally. This includes validation of the used KeyStrokes which detected some mistakes:

"Close all tabs." is now Ctrl+Alt+Shift+W.
"Find previous active match" is now Ctrl+L.
"Find next active match" is now Ctrl+Shift+L.

"Copy Throwable" does now have the shortcut "command shift alt T".
This was suggested by snstanton.
(Ticket #101)
SLF4J 1.6.4, Logback 1.0.1, Groovy 1.8.6, commons-lang 3.0.1, protobuf-java 2.4.1, jackson 1.9.2, jcommander 1.23, aspectj 1.6.11, cglib 2.2.2, httpclient 4.1.2, httpcore 4.1.3, commons-codec 1.5, JUnit 4.10, Spring 3.1.1.RELEASE

Known Issues

Flying Saucer related issues:

Selection in the HTML view is currently somewhat buggy, especially in case of scaled view.
See Issue 79: SelectionHighlighter not compatible with ScalableXHTMLPanel
The first line of the message in HTML view is not properly indented if it starts with whitespace. You can see this effect by examining the event created by LogPinupLargeRunnable (executed via "Log ASCII"). The HTML created is actually correct.
See Issue 125: <pre> ignores leading whitespace
Jumping to anchors is currently not supported so the navigation in help and details view isn't as good as it could be.
See Issue 105: URLs with anchors

Lilith may hang during startup while creating the preferences dialog. Just restart Lilith in that rare case.
This is caused by bug #6995182 and I can't do anything about it.
Sorry about it. It's a stupid Java-MediaTracker-ColorChooser-Bug with no workaround available.
m(

Attention

This release changes detailsView.groovy in a way incompatible with previous versions!

If you switch back to a previous version, you must reset this file. Simply execute "Preferences" => "Troubleshooting" => "Reinitialize details view files." in that case.

Previous Versions

0.9.41
0.9.40
0.9.39
0.9.38
0.9.37
0.9.36

Lilith 0.9.43

Download Now!
(Released: 2013-04-29)

Changes

Added ability to reconnect views after disconnect. All multiplex appenders are now creating a UUID upon startup and add that id to the logger context.
To revert to the old behavior, i.e. one view for every single connection, you can disable usage of UUID in the configuration of the appender.

<CreatingUUID>false</CreatingUUID>

This was suggested by Joe.
Added HTTP status codes 208, 226, 308, 420, 451, 508, 598 & 599.
Added 'filter' command that filters all events of an input file that match a given condition into an output file. This is faster than filtering in Lilith itself since the UI isn't eating up CPU while filtering.

This was suggested by Joe.
Added command line option to specify a custom logback configuration.
Added minimal logback configuration for command line commands.
Added support for log4j2.
Logback 1.0.12 introduced a change that broke LogbackShutdownServletContextListener.
Implemented ContextHelper to be compatible with both 1.0.12 and lower.
SLF4J 1.7.5, Logback 1.0.12, log4j 1.2.17, log4j2 2.0-beta5, Groovy 2.1.3, commons-io 2.4, commons-lang3 3.1, httpcore 4.2.4, httpclient 4.2.5, aspectj 1.7.2, jackson 2.2.0, jcommander 1.30, Spring 3.2.2.RELEASE, protobuf-java 2.5.0, jgoodies-looks 2.5.2, glazedlists 1.9.0, cglib 3.0, junit 4.11

Known Issues

Flying Saucer related issues:

Selection in the HTML view is currently somewhat buggy, especially in case of scaled view.
See Issue 79: SelectionHighlighter not compatible with ScalableXHTMLPanel
The first line of the message in HTML view is not properly indented if it starts with whitespace. You can see this effect by examining the event created by LogPinupLargeRunnable (executed via "Log ASCII"). The HTML created is actually correct.
See Issue 125: <pre> ignores leading whitespace
Jumping to anchors is currently not supported so the navigation in help and details view isn't as good as it could be.
See Issue 105: URLs with anchors

Lilith may hang during startup while creating the preferences dialog. Just restart Lilith in that rare case.
This is caused by bug #6995182 and I can't do anything about it.
Sorry about it. It's a stupid Java-MediaTracker-ColorChooser-Bug with no workaround available.
m(

Attention

This release changes detailsView.groovy in a way incompatible with previous versions!

If you switch back to a previous version, you must reset this file. Simply execute "Preferences" => "Troubleshooting" => "Reinitialize details view files." in that case.

Previous Versions

0.9.42.1
0.9.42
0.9.41
0.9.40
0.9.39
0.9.38
0.9.37
0.9.36

Lilith 0.9.44

Download Now!
(Released: 2014-04-21)

This release brings huge improvements to the usage of conditions. Take a look at "Focus" and "Exclude" in the popup and "Search" menu.

Remember that you can save conditions using Cmd/Ctrl-I. Those will show up in the "Saved conditions" section of "Focus" and "Exclude".

It will also most likely be the last Java 5 compatible version. Development will continue on Java 8.

Changes

The table of the view will now always receive the focus if the selected view changes.
Added alternative behavior for Focus/Exclude actions.
By default, those actions are replacing the current views filter, if available, with the new combined filter.
Hold shift to create a new view instead.
Status text is now properly updated in case of a replaced filter.
Renamed "Named" in the find combo to "Saved".
Renamed "Add condition..." to "Save condition..." and moved it from the "View" to the "Search" menu. Also added it to the popup menu.
Significantly enhanced tooltips of various condition-related components. They now show a pretty-printed string representation of the condition.
Enhanced "Focus" and "Exclude" popup menus.
Added corresponding "Focus" and "Exclude" menus to the "Search" menu.
Added two Substance look&feels to the mix.
Status text of main window is now properly updated on change of white/blacklisted list name.
Enhanced profiling output of TracingAspect.
Fixed of-by-one error in message renderer [+x lines]. Again.
servlet-api dependency of de.huxhorn.lilith.logback.servlet is now "provided".
Added "Paste StackTraceElement" (Cmd-shift V) which opens the respective source code in the IDE, if a proper plugin is installed.
ClassicLilithEncoder is now Encoder<ILoggingEvent> instead of Encoder<LoggingEvent>.
Fixed suppressed handling while parsing Throwables. This is also a partial workaround for LOGBACK-328.
Added fishing-for-compliments technology.
Groovy 2.2.2, Logback 1.1.2, SLF4J 1.7.7, Jackson 2.3.3, log4j2 2.0-beta9, rrd4j 2.2, aspectj 1.8.0, flying-saucer 9.0.4, Spring 4.0.2, macify 1.6, httpcore 4.3.2, httpclient 4.3.3, JCommander 1.35, servlet-api 3.0.1, jgoodies-looks 2.5.3, commons-lang3 3.3.2

Known Issues

Lilith is built with log4j2 2.0-beta9 and won't work with log4j2 2.0-rc1. The reason for this is that SocketAppender isn't working properly in that version.
See LOG4J2-542.
HTML tooltips are not working with the native Mac OS X menu bar so some tooltips, especially the nice condition tooltips, will look garbled. Use a different look&feel to circumvent this problem.
Unfortunately, I can't do anything about it.
Flying Saucer related issues:

Selection in the HTML view is currently somewhat buggy, especially in case of scaled view.
See Issue 79: SelectionHighlighter not compatible with ScalableXHTMLPanel
The first line of the message in HTML view is not properly indented if it starts with whitespace. You can see this effect by examining the event created by LogPinupLargeRunnable (executed via "Log ASCII"). The HTML created is actually correct.
See Issue 125: <pre> ignores leading whitespace
Jumping to anchors is currently not supported so the navigation in help and details view isn't as good as it could be.
See Issue 105: URLs with anchors

Lilith may hang during startup while creating the preferences dialog. Just restart Lilith in that rare case.
This is caused by bug #6995182 and I can't do anything about it.
Sorry about it. It's a stupid Java-MediaTracker-ColorChooser-Bug with no workaround available.
m(

Attention

This release changes detailsView.groovy in a way incompatible with previous versions!

If you switch back to a previous version, you must reset this file. Simply execute "Preferences" => "Troubleshooting" => "Reinitialize details view files." in that case.

Previous Versions

0.9.43
0.9.42.1
0.9.42
0.9.41
0.9.40
0.9.39
0.9.38
0.9.37
0.9.36

bitcoin: 19UjvmrDJMBcGDYQoFcrjYPqLRFPSwznZn
litecoin: LU6WM3nmGJy3N5PEE8yQwsAyenJs8dtbmV
dogecoin: DJC1R683hfD4VSEDAJrvNpv6GsCg8ewvhm

Lilith 8.0.0

Download Now!
(Released: 2015-11-15)

This version of Lilith requires Java 8 update 66 or higher and will says so if you try to start it with an older version.

You can still receive event from previous versions so if your application is still running Java 7 or lower just keep using the 0.9.44 artifacts.
Keep in mind that Java SE 7 End of Public Updates has already been reached.

It contains an important security fix related to deserialization and lots of small usability enhancements.

Changelog

Added

CHANGELOG.md in the spirit of Keep a CHANGELOG.
Rough TODO.md listing some things that should be done.
Error dialog if Lilith is started with Java prior to 1.8.0_66.
Added "Clear view" shortcut Cmd-K. K for clear.
Added lilith.version.bundle to system properties.
Displaying release notes of "newzest version" if already available.
Option to ignore the secondary identifier of event sources, ignoring by default.

Changed

Requires Java 8.
left-aligned most table cells.
Better view icons in Window menu. They now represent the state of the view, e.g. whether the connection is still alive and if a window of the view is already open.
Using EventQueue instead of SwingUtilities.
Using java.time.format instead of SimpleDateFormat or joda-time.
Renamed "Previous tab" to "Previous view" and "Next tab" to "Next view".
Changed "Next view" shortcut from Cmd-K to Cmd-J and "Previous view" shortcut from Cmd-J to Cmd-shift-J.
Switched "Next view" and "Previous view" in "View" menu.
Better error message in case of broken detailsView.
SimpleSendBytesService.DEFAULT_POLL_INTERVALL renamed to SimpleSendBytesService.DEFAULT_POLL_INTERVAL.
Removed BufferedOutputStream wrapper in SocketDataOutputStreamFactory. BufferedOutputStream prevented TimeoutOutputStream from working reliably.
reconnectionDelay in multiplex appenders is now long instead of int.
Using Groovy for Lilith logging configuration.
Recompressed images with latest ImageOptim version.
Better app icon on Mac. Thanks to Christian Balog!
Tried to ensure that license dialog is always visible.
Changed default of Show primary identifier even for named sources. preferences to false.
Enhanced Open inactive log... dialog.

Deprecated

Nothing.

Removed

Some HttpStatus enum values have been renamed. Code explicitly using them would need to be changed.
TroubleshootingPanel.reset(ViewContainer<?> container)
joda-time dependency.
stax-api and stax dependencies.

Fixed

Updated HttpStatus enum to RFC 7231, RFC 7232, RFC 7233, RFC 7235 and RFC 7238. Some enum values have been renamed in the process.
sulky SafeString is now always printing a Date as an ISO8601-DateTime with timezone UTC.
Using "127.0.0.1" instead of "localhost" in SerializingGoToSource to prevent IPv6 SNAFU.
Conditions-Focus/Exclude menu of detached windows are now updated on saved condition change.
Preventing useless focus traversal warnings in EventWrapperViewPanel and FindPanel.
Reduced log level of broken stream message in event producers.
Fixed initialization of "Attach/Detach" action.
Fixed statistics in case of Java != 1.6
Fixed "Focus" and "Exclude" menu tooltips on Mac. Those displayed HTML source if system menu bar was used.
Fixed Groovy links in help.
SLF4J 1.7.13, Logback 1.1.3, Spring 4.2.2, Groovy 2.4.5, commons-codec 1.9, commons-lang3 3.4, httpclient 4.5.1, httpcore 4.4.4, jackson 2.6.3, log4j2 2.4.1, aspectj 1.8.7, Thymeleaf 2.1.4, substance 7.3, protobuf 2.6.1, jcommander 1.48, glazedlists 1.9.1, servlet-api 3.1.0, flying-saucer 9.0.6, cglib 3.1, rrd4j 2.2.1

Security

Keep your Java version up-to-date. Lilith now demands the latest Java version.
Implemented whitelisting of classes allowed for deserialization to circumvent issues described in AppSecCali 2015: Marshalling Pickles - how deserializing objects will ruin your day.

Apache Commons statement to widespread Java object de-serialisation vulnerability
What Do WebLogic, WebSphere, JBoss, Jenkins, OpenNMS, and Your Application Have in Common? This Vulnerability.
Look-ahead Java deserialization

Known Issues

Garbled icons on Mac OS X 10.11. This is a bug in OS X. Supposedly #23164356.
The following text is written to stdout if this bug bites:

filter:2:47: error: excess elements in vector initializer
  return img.a * mix(c0, c1, dot(img.rgb, vec3(0,000000e+00, 0,000000e+00, 0,000000e+00)));
                                              ^                ~~~~~~~~~~
filter:1:6: error: non-void function should return a value
vec4 _falseColor(vec4 img, vec4 c0, vec4 c1) {
     ^

Filezilla ticket
Eclipse ticket

Flying Saucer related issues:

Selection in the HTML view is currently somewhat buggy, especially in case of scaled view.
See Issue 79: SelectionHighlighter not compatible with ScalableXHTMLPanel
The first line of the message in HTML view is not properly indented if it starts with whitespace. You can see this effect by examining the event created by LogPinupLargeRunnable (executed via "Log ASCII"). The HTML created is actually correct.
See Issue 125: <pre> ignores leading whitespace
Jumping to anchors is currently not supported so the navigation in help and details view isn't as good as it could be.
See Issue 105: URLs with anchors

Lilith may hang during startup while creating the preferences dialog. Just restart Lilith in that rare case.
This is caused by bug #6995182 and I can't do anything about it.
Sorry about it. It's a stupid Java-MediaTracker-ColorChooser-Bug with no workaround available.
m(

Attention

This release changes detailsView.groovy in a way incompatible with previous versions!

If you switch back to a previous version, you must reset this file. Simply execute "Preferences" => "Troubleshooting" => "Reinitialize details view files." in that case.

Previous Versions

0.9.44
0.9.43
0.9.42.1
0.9.42
0.9.41
0.9.40
0.9.39
0.9.38
0.9.37
0.9.36

Donate in Bitcoin. - 19UjvmrDJMBcGDYQoFcrjYPqLRFPSwznZn
Donate in Litecoin. - LU6WM3nmGJy3N5PEE8yQwsAyenJs8dtbmV
Donate in Dogecoin. - DJC1R683hfD4VSEDAJrvNpv6GsCg8ewvhm

Lilith 8.1.0

Download Now!
(Released: 2017-03-15)

This version of Lilith demands Java 8 update 121 or higher and will says so if you try to start it with an older version. It has also been tested with Java 9-ea+158.

You can still receive event from previous versions so if your application is still running Java 7 or lower just keep using the 0.9.44 artifacts.
Keep in mind that Java SE 7 End of Public Updates has already been reached.

Changelog

Added

Added TemporalAccessor support to SafeString.
Added log4j2 Marker support.
Added "Copy logger name" accelerator "command shift N".
Added "Copy message" accelerator "command shift C".
Added "Copy message pattern" accelerator "command shift alt C".
Added "Copy Throwable name" action with accelerator "command shift alt T".
Added "Throwable" condition.
Added "Focus Throwables"/"Exclude Throwables" matching events with any Throwable.
Added "Focus Throwable"/"Exclude Throwable" matching events with a specific Throwable class name.
Added "Copy call location" accelerator "command shift S".
Added "Copy call stack" accelerator "command shift alt S".
Added "Copy request URL".
Added "Copy request headers".
Added "Copy request parameters".
Added "Copy response headers".
Added thread priority to thread info of logging event.
Added "Copy thread name".
Added "Copy thread group name".
Added "ThreadName" condition.
Added "ThreadGroupName" condition.
Added "Focus Thread name"/"Exclude Thread name".
Added "Focus Thread group name"/"Exclude Thread group name".
Added "Focus Request URI"/"Exclude Request URI" menus.
Added lots of filter tests.
Added "Focus Request Parameter"/"Exclude Request Parameter".
Added "Focus Request Header"/"Exclude Request Header".
Added "Focus Response Header"/"Exclude Response Header".
Added alternative behavior for "MDC", "Request Parameter", "Request Header" and "Response Header" Focus/Exclude menu items. Pressing Alt while selecting Action will match any value for the given key.
Added support for ClassLoaderName, ModuleName and ModuleVersion in Java 9 StackTraceElement.
Added some more tips.
Added "Show unfiltered" accelerator "command U". Also added the action to the "Search" menu.
Added "Go to source" accelerator "command D". Also added the action to the "Edit" menu.

Changed

Using java.time.format instead of SimpleDateFormat.
Don't create copy of whitelist Set in WhitelistObjectInputStream.
Demand Java 8 1.8.0_121.
Added option to start application even if Java version requirements are not met.
Changed accelerator of "Copy Throwable" from "command shift alt T" to "command shift T".
Changed specification of HTTP status code 451 from draft to RFC 7725.
Changed meaning of ThrowableCondition. Condition now evaluates to true if search string is one of the Throwable contained in the hierarchy (including cause, suppressed) instead of only checking the root exception.
EventContainsCondition is now evaluating Throwable, NDC and any contained StackTraceElement values.
appendTo methods of ThrowableInfo and ExtendedStackTraceElement now throw a NullPointerException if StringBuilder is null.
ExtendedStackTraceElement.appendExtended is now private.
ExtendedStackTraceElement.toString(true) is now printing "na" instead of empty string if codeLocation or version is null.
HttpStatusTypeCondition understands more input. "SUCCESSFUL", "su", "2", "2X" and " 2x " will all evaluate to HttpStatus.Type.SUCCESSFUL.
CallLocationCondition understands more input. "at " and whitespace is now automatically removed.
HttpRemoteUserCondition is less strict. String is first trimmed for both condition and remote user of event. Empty string and "-" are both considered "no user name" and the condition matches accordingly.
MDCContainsCondition without value will now match if the MDC of an event contains any value (even null) for the given key.
SafeString/MessageFormatter changes. Those only have an effect if Lilith appenders are used.

String instances contained in Collection, Map or Object[] are now wrapped in apostrophes. This means that an empty Set will look differently than one containing an empty String. Similarly, a null element will look differently than 'null'.
Map instances are now formatted in Groovy style ([key:value, key2:value2]) instead of Java style ({key=value, key2=value2}).
byte[], Byte[] and Byte are now converted to hex values. Because [0xCA, 0xFE, 0xBA, 0xBE] has better readability than [-54, -2, -70, -66].
This is not a compatibility contest. It's about usability.

"Paste StackTraceElement" (command shift V) is now much more effective. It parses the text from the clipboard and opens the first StackTraceElement it finds in IDEA (if the necessary IDEA plugin is installed). Parsing is much more lenient.
Using SafeString for "Copy MDC".
Details view is now showing all available thread information.
XML is now handled by Woodstox.
Moved "Logger" in "Focus"/"Exclude" menus from bottom to top.
applicationUUID is now actually a ULID. The existing methods setCreatingUUID/isCreatingUUID and getUUID in the multiplex appenders are not renamed for compatibility reasons. ULID generation is handled in the new de.huxhorn.sulky:de.huxhorn.sulky.ulid module.
Activated automatic graphics switching on Mac, i.e. don't demand the high-performance, energy-hungry GPU. This fixes issue #27. Thanks to Nikita Belenkiy for the detailed issue.
Enhanced preferences dialog. This fixes issue #17.

Deprecated

Nothing.

Removed

Removed SourceInfo and related classes. They were all unused and also terrible.
Removed LoggingEvents and related classes. Same as above.
Removed AccessEvents and related classes. Same as above.
Removed unused methods getTextColor(), getBackgroundColor() and getBorderColor() of class SavedCondition.
Removed unused c'tors in AbstractFilterAction, AbstractLoggingFilterAction and AbstractAccessFilterAction.
Removed RRD statistics.
Removed unused SenderService and jMDNS.
Removed unused and broken UserNotificationLoggingEventHandler and UserNotificationAccessEventHandler.
Removed macify to ensure Java 9 compatibility.
Removed de.huxhorn.lilith.jul-slf4j-handler. Use org.slf4j:jul-to-slf4j and enable ch.qos.logback.classic.jul.LevelChangePropagator instead.
Removed Substance look & feel. The Insubstantial fork is broken in Java 9 and isn't maintained anymore. The just-revived original substance won't provide Maven artifacts because those are just "the latest chic".
Removed JGoodies look & feel. The current version is broken in Java 9 and the next version will be closed-source and payware.

Fixed

Make frames entirely visible after selecting them from the Windows Menu.
Added some more classes to deserialization whitelist. The missing classes prevented deserialization of some log4j2 events. This fixes issue #21.
Added another class to deserialization whitelist. The missing class prevented deserialization of logback 1.2.x events.
Fixed NPE in LoggingEventProtobufEncoder. This fixes issue #22.
Fixed NPE in CheckForUpdateRunnable in case of broken network connection.
Fixed handling of invalid XML created by java.util.logging.XMLFormatter. This fixes issue #26.
Being less strict about the required Java version. It seems certain Linux distros have a Java version string like 1.8.0_66-internal which is - strictly speaking - less than 1.8.0_66 since -internal is a pre-release identifier. Lilith will now accept versions like this if ignoring the pre-release identifier satisfies the version requirement.
Making sure selected event is reset when last view is closed.
log4j2 2.8.1, slf4j 1.7.24, Logback 1.2.1, jackson 2.8.7, Spring 4.3.7, Groovy 2.4.9, aspectj 1.8.10, httpclient 4.5.3, httpcore 4.4.6, commons-io 2.5, Thymeleaf 2.1.5, protobuf 3.2.0, jcommander 1.64, commons-lang3 3.5, flying-saucer 9.1.4

Security

Nothing.

Known issues

logback-access AccessEvent sent by SocketAppender isn't guaranteed to be deserializable at the moment. You can use the Lilith Multiplex Socket Appender in the meantime. See LOGBACK-1182 - Problem deserializing AccessEvent..
Logback 1.1.0 introduced some message formatting regressions. See LOGBACK-1183 - Message formatting regression.
Binary Lilith log files will only work in case of append=false. Implemented a workaround. See LOGBACK-1257 - Invalid files in case of append=true and Encoder with non-null headerBytes() / footerBytes()
log4j 1 won't be able to send ClassLoaderName, ModuleName and ModuleVersion for the call location of the event. Search LOG4J_MODULE in the source to take a look at the problem. Since Log4j 1 End-Of-Life has been announced 2015-08-06, chances are pretty slim that this will be fixed. Upgrade to log4j 2 or Logback.
Flying Saucer related issues:

Selection in the HTML view is currently somewhat buggy, especially in case of scaled view. See Issue 79: SelectionHighlighter not compatible with ScalableXHTMLPanel.
Jumping to anchors is currently not supported so the navigation in help and details view isn't as good as it could be. See Issue 105: URLs with anchors.

GLAZEDLISTS-469 - AutoCompleteSupport: Arrowing down on the popup and pressing enter fails to update combobox is happening in the find panel on macOS. Select the correct entry with the mouse as a workaround.

Previous Versions

8.0.0
0.9.44
0.9.43
0.9.42.1
0.9.42
0.9.41
0.9.40
0.9.39
0.9.38
0.9.37
0.9.36

Donate in Bitcoin. - 19UjvmrDJMBcGDYQoFcrjYPqLRFPSwznZn
Donate in Litecoin. - LU6WM3nmGJy3N5PEE8yQwsAyenJs8dtbmV
Donate in Dogecoin. - DJC1R683hfD4VSEDAJrvNpv6GsCg8ewvhm

Lilith 8.1.1

Download Now!
(Released: 2017-03-17)

This minor update mainly upgrades slf4j and logback versions to address a problem concerning serialized events with Markers.

Make sure to upgrade the versions in your application to slf4j 1.7.25 and logback 1.2.2.

See release notes of 8.1.0 for the full list of changes.

This version of Lilith demands Java 8 update 121 or higher and will says so if you try to start it with an older version. It has also been tested with Java 9-ea+158.

You can still receive event from previous versions so if your application is still running Java 7 or lower just keep using the 0.9.44 artifacts.
Keep in mind that Java SE 7 End of Public Updates has already been reached.

Changelog

Added

Added dependency versions to Troubleshooting section of preferences. This was suggested in issue #29 by @Pesegato.

Changed

Nothing.

Deprecated

Nothing.

Removed

Nothing.

Fixed

cglib 3.2.5, slf4j 1.7.25, logback 1.2.2

Security

Nothing.

Known issues

logback-access AccessEvent sent by SocketAppender isn't guaranteed to be deserializable at the moment. You can use the Lilith Multiplex Socket Appender in the meantime. See LOGBACK-1182 - Problem deserializing AccessEvent..
Logback 1.1.0 introduced some message formatting regressions. See LOGBACK-1183 - Message formatting regression.
Binary Lilith log files will only work in case of append=false. Implemented a workaround. See LOGBACK-1257 - Invalid files in case of append=true and Encoder with non-null headerBytes() / footerBytes()
log4j 1 won't be able to send ClassLoaderName, ModuleName and ModuleVersion for the call location of the event. Search LOG4J_MODULE in the source to take a look at the problem. Since Log4j 1 End-Of-Life has been announced 2015-08-06, chances are pretty slim that this will be fixed. Upgrade to log4j 2 or Logback.
Flying Saucer related issues:

Selection in the HTML view is currently somewhat buggy, especially in case of scaled view. See Issue 79: SelectionHighlighter not compatible with ScalableXHTMLPanel.
Jumping to anchors is currently not supported so the navigation in help and details view isn't as good as it could be. See Issue 105: URLs with anchors.

GLAZEDLISTS-469 - AutoCompleteSupport: Arrowing down on the popup and pressing enter fails to update combobox is happening in the find panel on macOS. Select the correct entry with the mouse as a workaround.

Previous Versions

8.1.0
8.0.0
0.9.44
0.9.43
0.9.42.1
0.9.42
0.9.41
0.9.40
0.9.39
0.9.38
0.9.37
0.9.36

Donate in Bitcoin. - 19UjvmrDJMBcGDYQoFcrjYPqLRFPSwznZn
Donate in Litecoin. - LU6WM3nmGJy3N5PEE8yQwsAyenJs8dtbmV
Donate in Dogecoin. - DJC1R683hfD4VSEDAJrvNpv6GsCg8ewvhm

Lilith 8.2.0

Download Now!
(Released: 2018-08-09)

This version of Lilith demands Java 8 update 181 or higher and will says so if you try to start it with an older version. It has also been built and tested with Java 10.0.2.

You can still receive event from previous versions so if your application is still running Java 7 or lower just keep using the 0.9.44 artifacts.
Keep in mind that Java SE 7 End of Public Updates has already been reached.

Changelog

Added

Added "Find previous active" and "Find next active" buttons to toolbar.
Added "Find previous" and "Find next" buttons to toolbar.
Added lots of missing mnemonics.
If the connection is lost then Message/RequestURI in table will now show "Connection closed." instead of nothing.
Added smooth horizontal table scrolling option that is enabled by default.
Added support for Log4j 2 JsonLayout, YamlLayout and XmlLayout. SerializedLayout has been deprecated in log4j2 2.9.0 so you should use one of the other options instead.
Added Automatic-Module-Names for artifacts where appropriate. See Automatic-Module-Name: Calling all Java Library Maintainers.

Changed

"Clean all inactive logs" is now less noisy in the Lilith log.
Changed icons for "Find previous active" and "Find next active". They now differ from "Find previous" and "Find next" as they should.
Refactored actions and icon handling.
Don't add null events to global logs.
Unchecking "Enable global logs." in Preferences is now deleting existing global log files automatically.
Keyboard help will now always be up-to-date.
Demand Java 8 1.8.0_181.

Deprecated

Nothing.

Removed

"Previous" and "Next" buttons in find panel.
"Pause" action. Pausing only paused updating of the table, not receiving of events. This was confusing (even me) and served no actual purpose. This action was a left-over from the early days of Lilith when it was used for debugging during development.

Fixed

All L&F support mac screen menu bar with Java 9 or higher.
Zero-delimited event receivers did not add a null event when end of stream was reached.
Fixed initial enabled state of "Go to source".
Fixed enabled state of "Edit" menu. Mustn't be disabled anymore because "Paste StackTraceElement" is always available.
Fixed enabled state of "Copy selection".
Menu entries related to global logs are now disabled if "Enable global logs." is unchecked in Preferences.
Added more dependencies and entries to the deserialization whitelist. This is essentially necessary because logback-access does not have an AccessEventVO. See also LOGBACK-1182 - Problem deserializing AccessEvent..
Not all event producers expect a heartbeat.
Made sure that "You have changed the look & feel." and "You have changed the application path." dialogs aren't hidden by the preferences dialog.
Fixed java executable detection in Windows bat file. Thanks, tha2015!
Logback 1.2.3, log4j2 2.11.1, Groovy 2.5.1, jackson 2.9.6, spring 5.0.8, protobuf 3.6.1, junique 1.0.4, jcommander 1.72, commons-lang 3.7, commons-text 1.4, commons-io 2.6, flying-saucer 9.1.14, glazedlists 1.10.0, aspectj 1.9.1, httpcore 4.4.10, httpclient 4.5.6, woodstox 5.1.0
Fixed several split package issues. Because of this, some classes have changed package names:

the two most commonly used classes de.huxhorn.lilith.logback.appender.ClassicMultiplexSocketAppender and de.huxhorn.lilith.logback.encoder.ClassicLilithEncoder have not been moved.
de.huxhorn.lilith.logback.encoder.AccessLilithEncoder changed to de.huxhorn.lilith.logback.encoder.access.AccessLilithEncoder.
de.huxhorn.lilith.logback.appender.AccessMultiplexSocketAppender changed to de.huxhorn.lilith.logback.appender.access.AccessMultiplexSocketAppender.
de.huxhorn.lilith.logback.appender.ClassicJsonMultiplexSocketAppender changed to de.huxhorn.lilith.logback.appender.json.ClassicJsonMultiplexSocketAppender.
de.huxhorn.lilith.logback.appender.ZeroDelimitedClassicJsonMultiplexSocketAppender changed to de.huxhorn.lilith.logback.appender.json.ZeroDelimitedClassicJsonMultiplexSocketAppender.
de.huxhorn.lilith.logback.appender.ClassicXmlMultiplexSocketAppender changed to de.huxhorn.lilith.logback.appender.xml.ClassicXmlMultiplexSocketAppender.
de.huxhorn.lilith.logback.appender.ZeroDelimitedClassicXmlMultiplexSocketAppender changed to de.huxhorn.lilith.logback.appender.xml.ZeroDelimitedClassicXmlMultiplexSocketAppender.

Security

Nothing.

Known issues

logback-access AccessEvent sent by SocketAppender isn't guaranteed to be deserializable at the moment. You can use the Lilith Multiplex Socket Appender in the meantime. See LOGBACK-1182 - Problem deserializing AccessEvent..
Logback 1.1.0 introduced some message formatting regressions. See LOGBACK-1183 - Message formatting regression.
Binary Lilith log files will only work in case of append=false. Implemented a workaround. See LOGBACK-1257 - Invalid files in case of append=true and Encoder with non-null headerBytes() / footerBytes()
log4j 1 won't be able to send Java 9 ClassLoaderName, ModuleName and ModuleVersion for the call location of the event. Search LOG4J_MODULE in the source to take a look at the problem. Since Log4j 1 End-Of-Life has been announced 2015-08-06, chances are pretty slim that this will be fixed. Upgrade to log4j 2 or Logback.
Flying Saucer related issues:

Selection in the HTML view is currently somewhat buggy, especially in case of scaled view. See Issue 79: SelectionHighlighter not compatible with ScalableXHTMLPanel.
Jumping to anchors is currently not supported so the navigation in help and details view isn't as good as it could be. See Issue 105: URLs with anchors.

glazedlists #485 - AutoCompleteSupport: Arrowing down on the popup and pressing enter fails to update combobox is happening in the find panel on macOS. Select the correct entry with the mouse as a workaround.

Previous Versions

8.1.1
8.1.0
8.0.0
0.9.44
0.9.43
0.9.42.1
0.9.42
0.9.41
0.9.40
0.9.39
0.9.38
0.9.37
0.9.36

Donate in Bitcoin. - 3MwD28iwF3faSvKUBYNe2XuCzStBi1NzAH
Donate in Bitcoin Cash. - qptxwv5la2war4v67f3yf47cxj59ca2s5vh4jz0tt9
Donate in Zcash. - t1TLsUKLsNczQbG4PVx7iNEyP5LtKauL3gr
Donate in Litecoin. - MPYHQnhjtv9nVFCoHF3UyPJAvhwqqZ2snx

Lilith 8.3.0

Download Now!
(Released: 2018-xx-xx)

This version of Lilith demands Java 8 update 181 or higher and will says so if you try to start it with an older version. It has also been built and tested with Java 10.0.2.

You can still receive event from previous versions so if your application is still running Java 7 or lower just keep using the 0.9.44 artifacts.
Keep in mind that Java SE 7 End of Public Updates has already been reached.

Changelog

Known issues

logback-access AccessEvent sent by SocketAppender isn't guaranteed to be deserializable at the moment. You can use the Lilith Multiplex Socket Appender in the meantime. See LOGBACK-1182 - Problem deserializing AccessEvent..
Logback 1.1.0 introduced some message formatting regressions. See LOGBACK-1183 - Message formatting regression.
Binary Lilith log files will only work in case of append=false. Implemented a workaround. See LOGBACK-1257 - Invalid files in case of append=true and Encoder with non-null headerBytes() / footerBytes()
log4j 1 won't be able to send Java 9 ClassLoaderName, ModuleName and ModuleVersion for the call location of the event. Search LOG4J_MODULE in the source to take a look at the problem. Since Log4j 1 End-Of-Life has been announced 2015-08-06, chances are pretty slim that this will be fixed. Upgrade to log4j 2 or Logback.
Flying Saucer related issues:

Selection in the HTML view is currently somewhat buggy, especially in case of scaled view. See Issue 79: SelectionHighlighter not compatible with ScalableXHTMLPanel.
Jumping to anchors is currently not supported so the navigation in help and details view isn't as good as it could be. See Issue 105: URLs with anchors.

glazedlists #485 - AutoCompleteSupport: Arrowing down on the popup and pressing enter fails to update combobox is happening in the find panel on macOS. Select the correct entry with the mouse as a workaround.

Previous Versions

8.2.0
8.1.1
8.1.0
8.0.0
0.9.44
0.9.43
0.9.42.1
0.9.42
0.9.41
0.9.40
0.9.39
0.9.38
0.9.37
0.9.36

Donate in Bitcoin. - 3MwD28iwF3faSvKUBYNe2XuCzStBi1NzAH
Donate in Bitcoin Cash. - qptxwv5la2war4v67f3yf47cxj59ca2s5vh4jz0tt9
Donate in Zcash. - t1TLsUKLsNczQbG4PVx7iNEyP5LtKauL3gr
Donate in Litecoin. - MPYHQnhjtv9nVFCoHF3UyPJAvhwqqZ2snx